# Richard Le

richardle1997@gmail.com

portfolio richard-le.com linkedin linkedin.com/in/le-rich github github.com/le-rich

A Computer Systems student with experience in game development and 3D visualization. I have a strong passion for the gaming industry as demonstrated by my <u>projects</u> and have a great admiration for the intersection between technology, design and creativity.

Skills	Programming	Software	Theory
	C# Java	Unreal Engine	Version Control
	C C++	Unity Engine	Agile Development
	Full-Stack Web	Blender	Gameplay Optimization
	MySQL	Adobe Suite	3D Rendering Concepts

### Game Jams

## Sunseeker

BC Game Jam 2019

1st Place - Blackbird Interactive Subtheme 1st Place - Offworld Industries Subtheme

You are a researcher stranded in space. Your only hope...a lone frenchman, survive for 5 days while he parties. Get energy orbs with your drone and refuel your base to stay alive.

Worked on: Core gameplay, Shader Code, Effects and VFX Scripting, Voice Acting Used: Unity, C#, Maya, Adobe Suite, HLSL

### **Indie Games**

# **Ecocity The Game**

Who can build the best eco-city? Is it you? Balance economy and ecology to build your own sustainable city. Available now at <u>ecothegamecity.ca</u> and on the google play store.

Worked on: Core Gameplay, 3D Animation, UI Scripting, Particle Effects Used: Unity, C#, MySQL, PHP

# Midnight Crown

An 'aerospace' combat flight game in atmosphere and zero-g. Featuring full 4 degrees of movement flight simulation, predictive guidance weapons, diegetic cockpits, complex AI behaviour trees with local avoidance and FMOD 3D Spatial audio to keep you on your toes. Built over the course of 1 Year as the sole developer.

Worked on: Everything! Gameplay, Art, Audio. Used: Unity, C#, Blender, FMODStudio, Adobe Suite

#### Roasted

Get your coffee beans and get ready for a last stand. You play as Joe, a barista, as an endless horde of angry hipsters make their way to your cafe. Defend yourself!

Worked on: Core Gameplay, VFX Scripting and Animation, UI and UX. Used: Unity, C#, Adobe Suite

## **Hackathons**

## **Canary**

Angelhack 2019

1st Place - Agora Challenge

A medical app that connects users to local trained volunteers who provide first-aid emergency medication before first responders reach a site. Current medication targets are Epinephrine, Insulin, Naloxone and CPR service.

Worked on: Google Maps Integration, Front-End UI, Project Management, Business Analysis

Used: Agora RTC, Google Cloud Platform, NodeJS, HTML, CSS, JS, JQuery

## <u>Visualeyes</u>

Bizhacks 2019

2nd Place - Best Buy Business Case

A Computer Vision/ Machine learning app that brings you to a product's storefront just by taking a photo of it.

Worked on: Camera Capture and Vision Analysis, Front-End UI and Animations Used: C#, Clarifai Computer Vision API

## **Experience**

## **Under the GUI Academy**

Feb 2017 - Present

Senior Staff Trainer, Junior Web Developer, Curriculum Creator, Game Dev Instructor

- Created all schooling curriculum: 7 Games and one theory CS Course
- Implemented front and backend features to a web-embedded game engine
- Added support for graphics libraries and support for more programming languages
- Consulting on Instructor Training and Curriculum Direction

Used: AWS, Full Stack Web, Python, Java, C#, Unity Game Engine

Oct 2017 - Apr 2018

# **COHO Labs, UBC**

Undergraduate Research Assistant

- Worked on streaming 3D geometry from architectural software to a game engine in real-time.
- App ran on Microsoft Hololens targeting AR.

Used: C#, Rhinoceros 5, Unity Game Engine

#### Education

# British Columbia Institute of Technology 2019 - 2022

BTech in Computer Systems Technology, 89% GPA

# University of British Columbia 2015 - 2018

Statistics and Computing Science Undergrad Courses

- Completed courses in Data Structures and Algorithms, Computer Architecture, Software Construction and more